<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathias Weidinger</title>
    <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mathias Weidinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intentional file structures in bash</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/post/2021-12-13-directories-org/directories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/post/2021-12-13-directories-org/directories/</guid>
      <description>Remember the times when, as a kid, you were only allowed to go out to play if you had cleared up the chaos in your room first? While we might not have appreciated our parents’ persistence on the matter all too much back then (I sure did not), I think most people would agree - once they’re adults, that is - that it helped them with building good habits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a data enthusiast who works at the intersection of environmental and development economics - or envirodevonomics for short. Following a nine month research assistantship with the Development Economics Group at ETH Zurich, I am currently finishing my Research Master&amp;rsquo;s at Maastricht University.
My research explores the linkages between ecosystem services, economic activity, and human development. The ultimate goal of my work is to find ways to tackle poverty, hunger, child mortality and the like through social protection, investment in environmental quality, and effective climate action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>In Progress   More Trees, Less Poverty?
  Specialization Choice and Switching Behavior in Public Policy Students (with Mindel van der Laar)
  Published   Senge, P., and Weidinger, M. (2020). MEP&amp;rsquo;s Receptiveness to Third Country Interests in the Framework of ACP-EU Parliamentary Diplomacy. NORTIA. [paper] [media] [bib]
  Weidinger, M. (2019). Ethno-national Confrontation and Electoral Choice. Peace and Progress 4(1), 3-29. [paper] [bib]
  Unpublished  Child Labour in Response to Climate Change [paper] [code] [bib]  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>  Statistics II, ETH Zurich (Spring 2022, Teaching Assistant)
  Git for Research, UNU-MERIT (Summer 2021, PhD workshop)
  Markdown and PanDoc, UNU-MERIT (Summer 2021, PhD workshop)
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vita</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/curriculum_vitae/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/curriculum_vitae/</guid>
      <description>For my achievements and mishaps to date, please see both my Curricula Vitae provided below. 1
 Curriculum Vitae: PDF CV of failures: PDF    Neither mentions my zeal of Latin grammar.&amp;#160;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;
   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
