<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathias Weidinger</title>
    <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mathias Weidinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Say Hi!</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you. You can send me an email at mathias.weidinger@gmail.com or book a meeting if you prefer an in-person conversation.
I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for interesting chats. Let&amp;rsquo;s brainstorm new ideas, challenge our assumptions, or scope the potential for collaboration over a cup of tea or coffee.
I check my inbox and reply to emails 1-2 times a day, but sometimes life gets in the way. Please follow up if I haven&amp;rsquo;t replied within a couple of days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing WBqueryR</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/post/2022-11-01-introducing-wbqueryr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/post/2022-11-01-introducing-wbqueryr/</guid>
      <description>Let me set the scene. You find yourself studying graduate economics and are tasked to compile as much household expenditure data from low- and middle-income countries - or LMICs - as you can possibly muster.1 You think you are smart and immediately navigate to the World Bank’s Microdata Library to search, find, and download household expenditure data on countries from Algeria to Zimbabwe.2 Not long into your quest, however, you start to get side-tracked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intentional file structures in bash</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/post/2021-12-13-directories-org/directories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/post/2021-12-13-directories-org/directories/</guid>
      <description>Remember the times when, as a kid, you were only allowed to go out to play if you had cleared up the chaos in your room first? While we might not have appreciated our parents’ persistence on the matter all too much back then (I sure did not), I think most people would agree - once they’re adults, that is - that it helped them with building good habits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>-- I am a social scientist with a passion for people and the natural world. Since 2023, I work as an Early Career Researcher at the Smith School of Enterprise and the Environment. I am also affiliated to Oxford Net Zero, the Institute of New Economic Thinking, the Environmental Change Institute, and Climate Compatible Growth. Before coming to Oxford, I worked with the Development Economics Group at ETH Zurich and studied at UNU-MERIT and Maastricht University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Work in Progress  Bridging the Financing Gap: Exploring the Drivers of Clean Energy Project Bankability in Ghana with Theophilus Acheampong, Dennis Asare, Amprofi Agyemang, and Bridget Menyeh. Submitted to Energy Policy
  Abstract  Access to finance remains a major constraint for many firms despite the potential of Sub-Saharan Africa&amp;rsquo;s clean energy sector to the drive the continent&amp;rsquo;s energy transition and access goals. This paper investigates the key factors influencing the bankability of clean energy projects in Ghana using Partial Least Squares Structural Equation Modelling (PLS-SEM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>  Trade and Economics (Summer 2024, Summer Spring Board) Statistics 2 (Spring 2022, ETH Zurich) Version Control: Git for Economists (2021, UNU-MERIT) Single Source Publishing of Quantitative Research (2021, UNU-MERIT)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vita</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/vita/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/vita/</guid>
      <description>Short Bio  Mathias Weidinger is a full-time research assistant in climate compatible growth at the Smith School of Enterprise and the Environment, University of Oxford. He received his B.A. in european studies from the Maastricht University in 2018, an M.Sc. in public policy and human development jointly awarded by UNU-MERIT and Maastricht University in 2021, and a research M.Sc. in economics from Maastricht University in 2023. His research focuses on environmental and ressource economics, development economics, and inferential methods for spatial data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
