<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mathias Weidinger</title>
    <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mathias Weidinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing WBqueryR</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/post/2022-11-01-introducing-wbqueryr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/post/2022-11-01-introducing-wbqueryr/</guid>
      <description>Let me set the scene. You find yourself studying graduate economics and are tasked to compile as much household expenditure data from low- and middle-income countries - or LMICs - as you can possibly muster.1 You think you are smart and immediately navigate to the World Bank’s Microdata Library to search, find, and download household expenditure data on countries from Algeria to Zimbabwe.2 Not long into your quest, however, you start to get side-tracked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intentional file structures in bash</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/post/2021-12-13-directories-org/directories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/post/2021-12-13-directories-org/directories/</guid>
      <description>Remember the times when, as a kid, you were only allowed to go out to play if you had cleared up the chaos in your room first? While we might not have appreciated our parents’ persistence on the matter all too much back then (I sure did not), I think most people would agree - once they’re adults, that is - that it helped them with building good habits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a quantitative social scientist who works at the intersection of environmental and development economics - or envirodevonomics for short. I combine data, mathematical models, and coffee to draw transition pathways towards net zero for low- and middle-income countries. I am particularly passionate about policies that leverage investments in environmental quality to promote the joint goals of environmental sustainability and human development, strengthen resilience in local communities, and make polluters pay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/lens/</guid>
      <description>I am a quantitative social scientist who works at the intersection of environmental and development economics - or envirodevonomics for short. I combine data, mathematical models, and coffee to understand how human societies and the natural environment relate to one another. I do research so that policies towards decarbonisation and conservation can be informed, effective, and fair - in particular by shifting the cost to polluters while lifting people out of poverty and strengthening global resilience through investments in environmental quality and adaptation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Work in Progress  The Hidden Costs of Deforestation: Evidence from Uganda (with Stephan Dietrich, Stafford Nichols, and Firminus Mugumya)  Unpublished Work   Weidinger, M. (2023). Does Exposure to Deforestation Affect Subjective Well-Being? Evidence from Sub-Saharan Africa. Master&amp;rsquo;s Thesis. [paper] [bib]
  Weidinger, M. (2021). Child Labour in Response to Climate Change. Master&amp;rsquo;s Thesis. [paper] [code] [bib]
  Earlier Work on European Politics   Senge, P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>ETH Zurich  Statistics 2 (Spring 2022, teaching assistant)  UNU-MERIT   Git for Research (Summer 2021, PhD workshop instructor)
  Markdown and PanDoc (Summer 2021, PhD workshop instructor)
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vita</title>
      <link>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/vita/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mathiasweidinger.github.io/vita/</guid>
      <description>Short Bio  Mathias Weidinger is a full-time research assistant in climate compatible growth at the Smith School of Enterprise and the Environment, University of Oxford. He received his B.A. in european studies from the Maastricht University in 2018, an M.Sc. in public policy and human development jointly awarded by UNU-MERIT and Maastricht University in 2021, and a research M.Sc. in economics from Maastricht University in 2023. His research focuses on environmental and ressource economics, development economics, and inferential methods for spatial data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
